I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
（泉(いずみ)）キャッ
（コユキ）うわ…
into the world of perfect free
たどりつく:to arrive at (after a struggle)/to finally reach/to find one's way to
（コユキ）
俺たちが たどりついたのは—
(You ain't no lonely!)
軒[のき]:eaves|narrow aisle surrounding the core of a temple building, 軒[けん]:counter for buildings (esp. houses)|suffix for a pen name, stage name, etc., 古ぼける[ふるぼける]:to look old/to become musty/to wear out, 釣堀[つりぼり]:fish pond
１軒の古ぼけた釣堀だった
You're gonna say I'm lying
I'm gonna get the chance
凶暴[きょうぼう]:brutal/atrocious/ferocious, 気をつける[きをつける]:to be careful/to pay attention/to take care
（コユキ）凶暴だから気をつけて！
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
いでる:to go/to come
あ…
（泉）おいで！
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
キャッ！ もう…
I was made to hit in America
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
We ended up at an old house
with a fishing hole.
He's vicious! Watch out!
C'mere!
犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|, 飼う[かう]:to keep (a pet or other animal)/to raise/to have
私 犬 飼ってたから
I used to have a dog.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
すごいよ 泉ちゃん
You're amazing, Izumi-chan.
えーと…
Hmm...
におい:odour/odor|aura
まず グーで においをかがせます
First, you let him sniff your fist.
犬[いぬ, イヌ]:dog (Canis (lupus) familiaris)|snoop (i.e. a detective, a spy, etc.)|loser|, 覚える[おぼえる]:to memorize|to learn|to feel|, させる:to make (someone) do|to allow (someone) to, させる:(usu. followed by a negative form) worth special consideration, ゆっくり:slowly/at ease/restful, なでる:to stroke/to caress|to comb (hair), あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
それで犬に覚えさせてから
ゆっくり なでてあげれば…
And when the dog knows your scent,
you stroke it very gently.
ウフフッ ほらね！
You see?
におい:odour/odor|aura
うん！ えー まず…
グーで においをかがせて—
'Kay.
First, you let him sniff your fist...
and then stroke his head...
頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||, なでる:to stroke/to caress|to comb (hair)
頭を… なでて…
いてる:to freeze/to be frozen over/to congeal
（コユキ）うあっ！ いててて…
いってぇ！ うう…
Beck! Stop it!
いてる:to freeze/to be frozen over/to congeal
（コユキ）うあっ！ いててて…
いってぇ！ うう…
（竜介）よう！
Yo!
Beck, go play by yourself.
（コユキ）竜介君…
Ryusuke-kun!
家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family
ここが… 竜介君の家？
Is this your house, Ryusuke-kun?
仕事場[しごとば]:place where one works/construction site/working area, でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
ああ 仕事場でもある
Yup. As well as my workplace.
迫力[はくりょく]:impressiveness/impact/force
（泉）なんか… 迫力あるねー
It has character.
Sorry, my house is old.
Well...you can use it however you like.
All right.
-See you tomorrow.
-Bye-bye, Grandma. See ya.
居心地[いごこち]:comfort
（竜介）ここさぁ…
何か 居心地いいんだよな
This place is really comfortable.
たくさん:a lot/lots|enough
（コユキ）
ＣＤ… たくさんありますねー
You have so many CDs.
それと…
-And...
-Lots of girls' romances, right?
女物[おんなもの]:women's goods, マンガ:cartoon/comic/comic strip, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（竜介）女物のマンガ
すごいだろ？
妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, 置く[おく]:to put|to leave (behind)|to establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.)||, ハマる:to fit|to be fit for (a job, etc.)|to fall into||
妹が置いてったのに
ハマっちゃったんだ
My kid sister left 'em,
and I got hooked on them.
少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period), マンガ:cartoon/comic/comic strip
（コユキ）少女マンガ…
Young girls' comics?
面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant
（竜介）これ 面白いぞ
This one's good.
Christy Sakuishi's "Happy Sangokushi".
ハッピー:happy, 三国[さんごく]:three countries|Japan, China & India|Three Kingdoms (of ancient China: Wei, Shu, Wu), 志[こころざし]:will|kindness|gift (as a token of gratitude)
クリスティ作石(さくいし)の
「ハッピー三国志」
（コユキ）あ！ それ知ってます
Oh, I know that one!
（泉）これ… わーっ！
Look! Wow!
これって—
This is a Dying Breed CD
from their indie days!
インディーズ:indies/independent film or music, 時代[じだい]:period|the times|oldness|
ダイブリがインディーズ時代に
出したＣＤじゃないですか？
（竜介）え？ うん そうだけど…
Huh? Oh yeah...
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), プレミア:premium, 付く[つく]:to be attached|to remain imprinted|to bear (fruit, interest, etc.)||, 付く[づく]:to become (a state, condition, etc.)
これって 今すごいプレミア
付いてるんですよー
This one's worth a lot now.
Oh yeah?
オーストラリア:Australia, バンド:band, カバー:cover/covering/dust jacket
（竜介）それ オーストラリアの
バンドのカバーなんだぜ
That cover's from the band, Australia.
聴く[きく]:to hear|to listen (e.g. to music)|to ask||
（泉）へー！ 聴きたいな～
Wow! I'd love to hear it!
オリジナル:original, 結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||, カントリー:country/countryside
（竜介）オリジナルは
結構カントリーでさ—
The original one was quite country.
Kinda like "Drag Car Boy."
ドラッグ:drag, カウボーイ:cowboy, 風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold
ドラッグ・カウボーイ風なんだ
ドラッグ:drag, カウボーイ:cowboy, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
（泉）あ ドラッグ・カウボーイなら
私も持ってます
Oh, I have "Drag Car Boy."
マニア:enthusiast
（竜介）うん エディのヤツ
マニアだからな
Eddie's totally into it.
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good
（コユキ）全然ついていけないや…
I can't follow their conversation at all.
（コユキ）ハァ…
-You than before
Close your eyes, no need to panic
Feel the void, feel the beat,
there's no need to say it
-Tomorrow will surely be wow wow
-Yukio! Telephone!
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（コユキの母）幸雄～ 電話よ！
-So cheer up,
because I want to see your smile
-Someone named Minami-san.
南[みなみ]:south, 南[ナン]:south wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of south wind tiles
南さんだって
（コユキ）南？ 男の人？
-So cheer up,
because I want to see your smile
-Minami? A man?
（コユキの母）アッハハハ…
もしもし:hello (e.g. on phone)|excuse me! (when calling out to someone)
もしもし… ああ 竜介君！
Hello?
Oh, Ryusuke-kun!
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, 日曜[にちよう]:Sunday
うん ライブ 日曜なんだね
Yeah. Live on Sunday, right?
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
うん 泉ちゃんにも伝えておくよ
Yup. I'll tell Izumi-chan too.
Uh-huh...Yup.
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
（竜介）それと お前に１つ
言っておきたいことがある
I also wanna tell you something.
え… 何？
Huh? What is it?
歳[さい]:-years-old|ability/gift, 歳[とし]:year|age|past one's prime
（竜介）お前は14歳 俺は16歳だ
You're 14. And I'm 16 years old.
呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
でもさ 俺のこと… 竜介って呼べよ
So just call me "Ryusuke".
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
男から“竜介君”なんて
呼ばれるとさ—
When a guy calls me "Ryusuke-kun",
it feels creepy.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
気持ちワリィんだ
聞こえる[きこえる]:to be heard/to be audible|to be said to be
聞こえてるか？
You listening?
おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
（竜介）おかしいか？
You think it's funny?
日本[にほん, にっぽん]:Japan, 社会[しゃかい]:society/public|social studies, 規則[きそく]:rules/regulations/conventions, 風土[ふうど]:natural features/topography/climate
日本社会の規則っていうか
風土っていうか…
So it's the Japanese way...
what society expects.
おい お前 聞いてるか？
But are you listening?
I'm just not into
feudalistic practices like that.
封建的[ほうけんてき]:feudal, しきたり:custom/convention/tradition, 苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of)
そういう封建的なしきたりって
苦手なんだ
コユキ？ 聞いてるか？
Koyuki, did you hear me?
Okay. I'll call you
just Ryusuke from now on.
呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
うん 竜介って…
これから そう呼ぶよ
日曜日[にちようび]:Sunday
それじゃ 日曜日に
I'll see you on Sunday.
のわぁっ！
遅れる[おくれる]:to be late/to be delayed/to fall behind schedule
ハァ… ハァ… 遅れてごめん！
Sorry I'm late!
Koyuki-san! What were you
doing at the intersection?
横断[おうだん]:crossing|traversing horizontally|cutting horizontally, 歩道[ほどう]:footpath/walkway/sidewalk, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
コユキさあ
横断歩道の所で何してたの？
Did you lose something?
落とす[おとす]:to drop|to clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.)|to lose (a match)||
何か落とした？ フッ
C'mon, let's go.
さ 行こう！
Ryusuke-kun drew me
this map to the live house.
書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
（コユキ）
これが竜介君が書いてくれた—
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, ハウス:house, 地図[ちず]:map
ライブハウスの地図なんだ
-All simple hiragana.
-I guess he can't write kanji.
ひらがな:hiragana/cursive Japanese syllabary used primarily for native Japanese words (esp. function words, inflections, etc.)
（コユキ）ひらがな…
漢字[かんじ]:Chinese characters/kanji, 苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
漢字 苦手みたい
Say, Izumi-chan.
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
（コユキ）ねぇ 泉ちゃん
Hmm? What is it?
（泉）ん… 何？
Why don't you start seeing Ryusuke-kun?
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other
（コユキ）竜介君と つきあえば？
I mean, he's cool...
カッコ:parentheses/brackets, カッコ:shape/form/figure
だって…
竜介君ってカッコいいしさ
Oh, right! I want you to
listen to something, Koyuki!
聴く[きく]:to hear|to listen (e.g. to music)|to ask||, ものがある:sentence-ending expression of strong judgement
あ そうだ！
コユキに聴かせたいものがあるの
Here it is.
あった あった… はい
This.
This is Dying Breed.
ブリード:bleeding (e.g. dyes)/seepage
これが ダイイング・ブリード
What's the matter?
どうした？
This is...
（コユキ）これ…
Oh, sorry! The battery's dead!
電池[でんち]:battery/cell, 切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||
（泉）あ ごめん！ 電池切れてるね
Izumi-chan!
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain
（カヨ）泉ちゃ～んっ！
Oh, Kayo-chan! You're late!
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|
あっ カヨちゃん 遅いぞー！
Sorry, sorry!
（カヨ）ワリィ ワリィ
Dying...Breed.
ブリード:bleeding (e.g. dyes)/seepage
ダイイング… ブリード…
Koyuki, hurry it up!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
コユキー 早くー！
We'll leave you behind!
置く[おく]:to put|to leave (behind)|to establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.)||
（カヨ）置いてっちゃうぞー
This way.
（泉）こっち こっち
Hey!
おーい:hey!/oi!|I
（カヨ）おーい
This is...an interesting place.
面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant
（コユキ）面白い… とこだね
-Oh, there's a good crowd.
-Yeah.
集まる[あつまる]:to gather/to collect/to assemble, じゃん:isn't it
（カヨ）おー 集まってるじゃん
（コユキ・泉）うん
These are tonight's bands.
きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 出演[しゅつえん]:performance/stage appearance|to act (in a play), バンド:band
（カヨ）
これが きょうの出演バンドだよ
ふーん:hmm/well ...|roughly
（コユキ・泉）ふーん…
What's wrong, Koyuki?
（泉）どうしたの コユキ？
A live house...
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, ハウス:house
（コユキ）ライブハウス…
Wait! That's-!
（泉）あっ そっちは…
Cut the crap!
ふざける:to joke/to jest|to make fun of
（栄二(えいじ)）ふざけるな！
Can't you listen to me?!
聞ける[きける]:to tell
俺の言うことが聞けないのか！
The entire band agreed to it.
バンド:band, 考え[かんがえ]:thinking|idea|intention||
（栄二）バンドみんなの考えだ
I like my black hair.
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 髪[かみ]:hair (on the head), 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
俺は自分の黒い髪が好きなんだ
Hey, thanks for coming.
ああ よく来たな
Err...Umm...
（コユキ）あ… いや…
Ryusuke...
竜介…
If you expect to be a pro,
you'd better listen to me.
やっていく:to live/to make a living/to get on with
お前もプロとして
やっていくつもりなら—
俺の言うことを聞け！
白い[しろい]:white, 衣装[いしょう]:clothing/costume/outfit
フッ… この前の白い衣装
サイアクだったぜ
That white outfit
the other time was the pits.
-Stop it!
-That's enough!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, かげん:(moon's) last quarter, かげん:lower limit|infimum
（ボーカル）やめろよ！
いいかげんにしろ！
There's a scout in the audience tonight!
きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil, 事務所[じむしょ]:office
きょうは事務所の人が
見に来てるんだぞ
With any luck, we can quit our
part-time jobs and focus on our music!
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious, バイト:work (esp. part time or casual), やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（東郷(とうごう)）俺たち
うまくいきゃ バイトやめて—
離す[はなす]:to separate/to part/to divide
（竜介）離せよ！
音楽[おんがく]:music/musical movement, 集中[しゅうちゅう]:concentration/convergence/centralization
音楽に集中できるんだぞ！
-Understand?!
-Eiji!
分かってんのかよ！
（ボーカル）
栄二… 栄二！
-Leggo of me!
-Eiji!
離す[はなす]:to separate/to part/to divide
（栄二）離せって！
-Let's go.
-Yeah...
（泉）行こう…
（コユキ）うん
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（ボーカル）
頼む！ やめろ！
Stop it!
They were really going at it.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 迫力[はくりょく]:impressiveness/impact/force
何か すごい迫力
They're all serious about this.
So they get uptight.
イラつく:to get irritated
（カヨ）みんなマジなんだ
イラついてんのさ
It's 1500 yen, right?
円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
（コユキ）1,500円ですよね
-Plus 500 yen for drinks.
-Here you go.
ドリンク:drink, 代[しろ]:substitution|material|price||, 代[よ]:world/society/age, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
（受付係）ドリンク代 500円ですー
（コユキ）はい
-All we need is get into the night
-So this is a live concert...
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance
（コユキ）これが… ライブ…
-People need it
-Wow...
-get into the night
-Maho...Minami.
南[みなみ]:south, 南[ナン]:south wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of south wind tiles, 真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind
南… 真帆(まほ)
-Let it the funk
-Maho...Minami.
歳[さい]:-years-old|ability/gift, 歳[とし]:year|age|past one's prime, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend
14歳 俺の妹だよ
（コユキ）え？
-Ain't a thing
-14 years old.
-All we need is
-My kid sister.
-Get into the night
Let it the funk
イェイ:yay
イェイ！
We got to move in the world destruction
-Get in tha funky punky!
-Yeah!
シリアル:serial
（カヨ）「シリアル・ママ」
Serial Mama.
バンド:band
それが竜介君のいるバンドの名前？
Is that the name of Ryusuke-kun's band?
たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous, 栄[ロン]:winning by picking up a discarded tile, 栄[えい]:glory/prosperity, 二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two
うん たぶん栄二君が
つけたんじゃないかな
Yeah. Eiji-kun probably picked the name.
シリアル:serial
シリアル・ママ…
Serial Mama...
栄[ロン]:winning by picking up a discarded tile, 栄[えい]:glory/prosperity, 二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two
栄二君 １年前に—
A year ago, Eiji-kun said he was
gonna make the ultimate band.
最強[さいきょう]:strongest, バンド:band, つくる:to make/to produce|to prepare (food)
最強のバンドをつくるんだ！
って みんなに言ってさ
最強[さいきょう]:strongest, バンド:band
（コユキ・泉）最強のバンド？
-The "ultimate band"?
誘う[さそう, いざなう]:to invite/to ask|to tempt, かなり:considerably/fairly/quite, 強引[ごういん]:overbearing/coercive/pushy
竜介君 誘うのも
かなり強引だったそうだよ
Apparently, he really bugged
Ryusuke-kun about joining.
ねえ カヨちゃん
あの人かな？
Say Kayo-chan...Is that him?
事務所[じむしょ]:office
ああ 事務所の人ね
Oh yeah, from the production company.
Eiji-kun's friend brought him.
栄[ロン]:winning by picking up a discarded tile, 栄[えい]:glory/prosperity, 二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two, 知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance, 連れる[つれる]:to lead/to take (a person), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
栄二君の知り合いが
連れてきたみたい
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious, メジャー:major, デビュー:debut, 夢[ゆめ]:dream
うまくいけば メジャーデビューも
夢じゃないかも
If things go well, a major debut
may no longer be just a dream.
-What do you think?
-Looks good.
あの２人 大丈夫かな？
I wonder if those two are okay.
そうなんだよ
I know! It's like they have two leaders,
リーダー:leader, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
リーダーが
２人いるみたいでさ
ハラハラ:to feel anxious/to feel nervous/to be kept in suspense
見てても
ハラハラしちゃうんだ
and it's nerve-wracking just watching them.
（男性）大丈夫ったい
（泉）ん？
Don't worry about 'em.
個性[こせい]:individuality/personality/idiosyncrasy
（男性）違う個性が—
Two opposites with perfect techniques
combine to create that sound!
抜群[ばつぐん, バツグン]:preeminence/distinction|outstanding, 共鳴[きょうめい]:resonance/sympathetic (sound)/(being in) sympathy, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|, サウンド:sound
抜群のテクで
共鳴し合(お)っとうサウンド！
ツイン:twin, リード:lead/leading/taking the lead, ギター:guitar, 正直[しょうじき]:honesty/integrity|honestly, 感動[かんどう]:being deeply moved emotionally/excitement/passion
あのツインリードギターは
正直 感動もんやけぇ！
Those two lead guitars...
Man, talk about music!
シリアル:serial
シリアル・ママ…
ばりサイコーったい！
Serial Mama...They are the best!
始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from)
おっ 始まるよ
Oh, they're up.
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer
もっと前で見よう！
Let's go up closer!
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
（女性客１）イェーイ！
Yay!
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, 愛する[あいする]:to love
（女性客２）
栄二～！ 愛してる～！
Eiji! I love you!
イヤッホー:whoopie/yee-haw/noise made when celebrating
（男性）イヤッホー！
（コユキ）わぁっ
ヤッホゥ！
Yahoo!
シリアル:serial
（ボーカル）
シリアル・ママでーす！
We're the Serial Mama!
（ボーカル）あれ おっかしいなー
Hey! That's weird!
直す[なおす]:to cure|to fix|to do over again (after -masu base of verb)||
すんませーん！
今 直すんで ちょっと待ってねー
Sorry about that!
We'll get it fixed, just a sec!
告知[こくち]:notice/announcement
え～っと この時間使って
告知タ～イム！
Hmm...Let's use this time
for some chit-chat!
んー 栄二
アレ言っちゃっていいのか？
Eiji, can I tell them that?
Boy, that was a shock.
Does this happen often?
ビックリ:to be surprised/to be amazed/to be frightened
ビックリしたぁ
こういうことって
よくあるんですか？
ギター:guitar, 弦[つる]:bowstring|string (of shamisen, guitar, violin, etc.)|bail (arched pot handle)|, 弦[げん]:bowstring|string (of a shamisen, etc.)|chord|, 切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||
ギターの弦が切れる
なんてーのは まあ—
A guitar string will break sometimes.
よくあるけど—
ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent, めった:thoughtless/reckless|seldom (with neg. verb)
ここまでひどいのは
めったにないよ
But something this bad never happens.
What a day for it to happen...
しかも:moreover/furthermore|nevertheless, きょう:imperial capital (esp. Kyoto)|final word of an iroha-uta, きょう:bad luck/bad fortune|evil
しかも きょうは…
スタッフ:staff, ギター:guitar, ライン:line, つなぐ:to connect/to link together|to tie, つなぐ:rigging, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
（スタッフ１）ギターのライン
Ｃ-１つないでみてくださーい！
Can you connect the guitar line to C1?
スタッフ:staff, 了解[りょうかい]:comprehension/consent/understanding
（スタッフ２）了解ですー！
Got it!
シールド:shield, 問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
（竜介）シールドは問題ない
My shield is fine.
切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||
（栄二）こっちはダメだ
切れちゃってるぞ
Not mine. It's broken.
スタッフ:staff, 他[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 他[た]:other (esp. people and abstract matters), 代用[だいよう]:substitution
（スタッフ１）
はい 他ので代用します！
I'll switch it!
男性[だんせい]:man/male|masculine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
（男性客１）まだかよ！
-How long's it gonna take?!
-Hurry it up!
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
（女性客３）早くしてー
男性[だんせい]:man/male|masculine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, 始める[はじめる]:to start|to open (e.g. a store)|to start ...
（男性客２）始めろー！
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
（女性客４）栄二～！
エフェクター:effector, ボリューム:volume (sound level), 下がる[さがる]:to come down|to hang|to move back||
そっか エフェクターの
ボリュームが下がってたんだ
I got it. The effecter volume was too low.
栄二！
Eiji!
オーケー:OK
おう！ こっちもオーケーだぜ！
Yo! I'm okay on my side!
スタッフ:staff
（スタッフ１）すみません！
お待たせしました
Thank you for your patience! Let's go!
オーケー:OK
オーケーです！
You're the best!
男性[だんせい]:man/male|masculine gender, 客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, シリアル:serial
（男性客３）
シリアル・ママ サイコー！
おっと:husband, おっと:uh-oh/oops/sorry
おっと？
Huh?
ハァ… ハァ…
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
They're having a wrap party
at a pub up the street.
この先[このさき]:beyond this point/from now on/after this, 居酒屋[いざかや]:izakaya/informal Japanese gastropub, 打ち上げる[うちあげる]:to launch|(of waves) to dash|to finish (e.g. a theater run, sumo tournament)|, 打ち上げる[ぶちあげる]:to make a bold speech/to make a bold statement
（泉）この先の居酒屋で
打ち上げあるってさ
-Won't you join us, Koyuki?
-Yeah.
コユキも行かない？
泉[いずみ]:spring/fountain, 耳[みみ]:ear|hearing|edge|, 平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right
（コユキ）うん…
ねえ 泉ちゃんは耳 平気？
Hey, Izumi-chan, are your ears okay?
ライブ:live (esp. concert, show, etc.)/live performance, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
（泉）んー？ ハハッ そっか
コユキはライブ初めてだもんね
Oh, that's right. It was your
first time at a live concert.
Don't worry. Your hearing
will return in a bit.
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（カヨ）
大丈夫だよ そのうち戻るよ
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
（コユキ）俺 うちに電話してくる
（泉）じゃあ 先に行ってるね
I'm going to call home.
We'll go on ahead.
"Pub New Shinshu"
-Okay, three orders of chuhai.
-Hey, gimme some beef tongue.
酎ハイ[ちゅうハイ, チューハイ]:shochu highball/cocktail of shochu with tonic water, 丁[ちょう]:counter for sheets, pages, leaves, etc.|counter for blocks of tofu|counter for long and narrow things such as guns, scissors, spades, hoes, inksticks, palanquins, candles, jinrikishas, shamisen, oars, etc.||, 丁[てい, ひのと]:4th in rank/fourth sign of the Chinese calendar|Denmark
（店員）はーい 酎ハイ３丁！
牛タン[ぎゅうタン]:beef tongue (a specialty of Sendai)/ox tongue, ちょう:counter for long and narrow things such as guns, scissors, spades, hoes, inksticks, palanquins, candles, jinrikishas, shamisen, oars, etc., ちょう:counter for sheets, pages, leaves, etc.|counter for blocks of tofu/counter for servings in a restaurant
（客）おねーさん
牛タンちょうだーい
"Pub New Shinshu"
Hey, Eiji-kun and Ryusuke haven't
exchanged a word since the fight.
栄[ロン]:winning by picking up a discarded tile, 栄[えい]:glory/prosperity, 二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two
（カヨ）
ねえねえ 栄二君と竜介—
（店員）はいよー
栄[ロン]:winning by picking up a discarded tile, 栄[えい]:glory/prosperity, 二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two
（カヨ）
ねえねえ 栄二君と竜介—
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
あれから全然話してないよ～
ヒック…
Hey, Eiji-kun and Ryusuke haven't
exchanged a word since the fight.
Geez...This band is really in trouble.
バンド:band, ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
このバンド マジヤバいかもよー
What are you saying, girl?!
言いよる[いいよる]:to court/to woo/to approach defiantly, おねえさん:elder sister|(vocative) young lady
なーんば言いよっとですか～
おねえさん！
The Eiji and Ryusuke duo
will be together forever!
コンビ:combination/pair/duo, 永遠[えいえん]:eternity/perpetuity/immortality, 不滅[ふめつ]:immortal/undying/indestructible
栄二と竜介のコンビは
永遠に不滅ったい！
トイレ:toilet/restroom/bathroom
あ… 俺 トイレ
I'm going to the john.
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
（カヨ）ヒック… マジヤバい
This is the pits!
不滅[ふめつ]:immortal/undying/indestructible
（男性）
不滅ったい…
ハァ…
Say, this is the toilet, right?
（真帆）ねえ！
（コユキ）ん…
トイレ:toilet/restroom/bathroom
（真帆）これって トイレだよね？
Oh, you're Ryusuke-kun's younger sister.
妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend
あー 竜介君の妹さん！
トイレ:toilet/restroom/bathroom
うん… これってトイレ？
-Is this the toilet?
-Yeah, I think so.
（コユキ）うん そうだと思う
Thanks.
サンキュー:thank you
サンキュー
Oh, I see. Maho-chan,
you're not good with kanji either.
真帆[まほ]:spread-out sail/full sail/(sailing) downwind, 漢字[かんじ]:Chinese characters/kanji
（コユキ）そっか 真帆ちゃんも
漢字ダメなんだね エヘヘ…
What?!
Who the fuck are you?!
Idiot.
（真帆）バーカ
Dammit!
（カヨ）ちくしょー！
（男性）
ぬあーっ このアマ～！
-You wench!
-You got Serial Mama all wrong!
ふざける:to joke/to jest|to make fun of, シリアル:serial
（カヨ）
ふざけんじゃねーぞ このヤロー
お前 シリアル・ママって—
回[かい]:counter for occurrences|a time|inning (baseball)||, っつう:meaning/called/said
10回言ってみろっつうんだよ！
Where's the sake?! Bring the sake!
酒[さけ, ささ]:alcohol/sake, 持ってこい[もってこい]:just right/ideal|fetch!
（カヨ）
酒 持ってこい 酒～！
-Shut up!
-Screw you!
ふざける:to joke/to jest|to make fun of
ふざけんなよ お前！
Pankration began in ancient Greece,
古代[こだい]:ancient times, ギリシャ:Greece, 発祥[はっしょう]:origin|appearance of auspicious omen, パンクラチオン:pankration (ancient Greek martial art)
（教師）古代ギリシャで発祥した
パンクラチオンが—
and in modern England, it became
popular as the Lancashire style
近代[きんだい]:present day/modern times, イギリス:Great Britain/United Kingdom
近代イギリスにおいて—
スタイル:figure/body build, 定着[ていちゃく]:taking hold/getting attached/becoming established, 現在[げんざい]:now/current/present
ランカシャースタイルとして
定着し 現在の—
and was adapted into what
we know today as free-style wrestling.
フリースタイル:freestyle, レスリング:wrestling
フリースタイルレスリングに
なったわけだ
And many wrestlers
have come up the ranks
数々[しばしば]:often/again and again/frequently, 数々[かずかず]:many/numerous/various, レスラー:wrestler, 生み出す[うみだす]:to create|to invent|to give birth to
数々の名レスラーを生み出した
ビリー・ライレージム—
after going through
the notorious Snake Pit.
通称[つうしょう]:popular name/nickname/alias, スネーク:snake, ピット:pit, 出身[しゅっしん]:person's origin (e.g. city, country, parentage, school), レスラー:wrestler
通称スネーク・ピット出身の
レスラーとして—
And famous among them is Karl Gotch.
有名[ゆうめい]:famous|fame, カール:curl
有名なのは カール・ゴッチ！
-Want to listen to this?
-Can I borrow it?
聴く[きく]:to hear|to listen (e.g. to music)|to ask||
（泉）これ 聴いてみる？
借りる[かりる]:to borrow/to have a loan|to rent
（コユキ）いいの？ 借りて
もちろん:of course/certainly/naturally
もちろん！
Of course!
Ryusuke-kun is really something.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
竜介君って すごいよね
Yeah.
I hope you find something
to get passionate about, too.
見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
コユキにも 何か見つかるといいね
Yeah.
You can give it back anytime.
返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
（泉）返すの いつでもいいから
See you!
じゃあ また！
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
（コユキ）あ… ありがとう！
Thanks!
I think Ishiguro-sempai
may have a thing for you.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
（田辺(たなべ)）石黒先輩…
お前のこと 好きなのかも
-I don't think so...
-Neither do I.
そんなこと…
（田辺）ないよなー
Say, Ishiguro. You've been
awfully cheerful lately.
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 元気[げんき]:lively/full of spirit|healthy
（女子生徒１）なんかさー
最近 石黒 元気だよねぇ
（泉）えー そうかなぁ？
You think so?
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 怪しい[あやしい]:suspicious/dubious|charming
（女子生徒２）おっ 怪しいぞー
（泉）ウフッ
I'm suspicious!
It was a mistake. You and me joining up.
失敗[しっぱい]:failure/mistake/blunder, 組む[くむ]:to cross (legs or arms)|to put together|to braid||, 自体[じたい]:itself|one's own body|originally
失敗だったんだ…
俺とお前が組むこと自体
Yes?
はい… いえ 大丈夫です
No, it's all right.
Yes, I'll be right there!
伺う[うかがう]:to ask|to implore (a god for an oracle)|to visit|, 失礼[しつれい, しつらい]:discourtesy|Excuse me|to leave|
はい すぐに伺います
はい 失礼します！
Yes, thank you!
It's the weekend,
and I can't even take off!
週末[しゅうまつ]:weekend, 休める[やすめる]:to rest/to suspend/to give relief
週末だって休めないんだ
Hard luck.
大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||
大変だな
You wouldn't understand
what I have to go through.
苦労[くろう]:troubles/hardships
お前には 俺の苦労は分かんねえよ
Not you, a CEO's son.
社長[しゃちょう]:company president/manager/director, 息子[むすこ, そく]:son|penis
社長の息子のお前には分かんねえよ
Ryusuke...
竜介…
I'm going to form the ultimate band.
最強[さいきょう]:strongest, バンド:band, つくる:to make/to produce|to prepare (food)
俺は… 最強のバンドをつくる
So will I.
つくる:to make/to produce|to prepare (food)
俺も つくるよ
Ryusuke-kun...
竜介君…
Another minute
Feelin' so fine
You turn the freeze
into warm light
Had a premonition
I've been waitin' ever since
My world comin' down
It's got me spinnin' 'round
If you really wanna fly
you gotta let go
Simply the most
big sensation
(once you're here you won't go back)
She's really pretty
One-eyed vision
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Little sister showed me
Really took me for a ride
My world comin' down
(once you're here you won't go back)
(lose the fear it don't come back)
Lately, I'm really into the love game!
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, ラブゲーム:love game (tennis, badminton)/game won without the opponent scoring, ハマる:to fit|to be fit for (a job, etc.)|to fall into||
（千葉(ちば)）
最近 ラブゲームにハマってまーす
"Next Episode"
Lately, I'm really into the love game!
Just kidding.
ウソでーす
"Next Episode"